Emanuele Sansone

Website: http://emsansone.github.io/ GitHub: https://github.com/emsansone Email: e.sansone@hotmail.it

Summary

I'm a researcher in the field of machine learning. Previously, I was studying the use of unlabeled data to support decision making, in the form of semi-supervised, positive unlabeled and unsupervised learning. I'm currently interested in using data and machine learning to perform reasoning tasks, in particular to automate the process of theorem proving. I have excellent organizational, communication and presentation skills developed over different teaching and supervising experiences at university as teaching assistant and in sports as ski coach and ski master instructor.

Education

2013-2018

Ph.D.

ICT doctoral school, University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Towards Uncovering the True Use of Unlabeled Data in Machine Learning"

Advisor: Prof. Francesco G.B. De Natale.

Dissertation on the usage of unlabeled data in different areas of machine learning, including unsupervised,

positive unlabeled and semi-supervised learning.

2011-2012

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering (cum laude)

University of Trento, Italy

110/110 summa cum laude | Gpa: 28.82/30

Thesis: "Multimodal Photo Galleries Synchronization"

Advisor: Prof. Nicola Conci, Giulia Boato.

Computer vision application for automatic synchronization of photo galleries from multiple users attending

the same event (C++ language).

2008-2010

B.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering

University of Trento, Italy

Thesis: "Master P-NET protocol implementation on PIC 32 architecture"

Advisor: Prof. Dario Petri, Eng. Michele Corrà.

Programming a master device in a network composed by different sensors and actuators. Implementation of P-NET protocol over a PIC 32 microcontroller (C language).

Work and Research Experience

2018-2020

Research Scientist

Huawei Technologies R&D, London, UK

Doing research in the area of deep generative models and self-supervised learning. Writing white papers and patenting ideas. Supervising students on using machine learning for applications related to the company: Yinbai Li (Bachelor student in Mathematics at University of Cambridge), Xingyu Jin (Master student in Computer Science at University of Edinburgh).

2018-to date

Reviewer

Serving as a reviewer for international journals in the area of machine learning and signal processing, such as IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems, Machine Learning (Springer) and IEEE Transactions on Image Processing.

2015-2016

Research Internship

LAMDA group, Nanjing University, China

Advisor: Prof. Zhi-Hua Zhou.

Working on positive unlabeled learning and participating in reading groups.

Academic Experience

2016 Teaching Assistant, Computer Vision (Code 140266)

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Goal: provide an introductory view of machine learning and neural networks. [Sample Material]

Tasks (frontal lessons): Basic notions of statistical learning theory. Introduction to neural networks and derivation of the backpropagation algorithm. Building a binary classifier with neural networks (with demo in Matlab). Extending the classifier to multiclass classification (with demo in Matlab).

Tasks (lab sessions for the main course): Introduction to OpenCV and explanation/ implementation of SIFT descriptors.

Case study/Project description: design and implementation of a neural network classifier for positive unlabeled learning

Students' supervision and Assessment: Federico Morelli, Davide Piscini, Subhankar Roy, Alessandro Antonucci, Pietro Postal, Andrea Simonelli, Stefano Leornardelli, Giulio Carlo Gialanella, Davide Zanetti, Adriano Tomasi.

2015 Teaching Assistant, Multimedia Networking (Code 140151)

M.Sc. in Telecommunications Engineering, University of Trento, Italy

Goal: provide an introductory view of video compression/coding. [Sample Material]

Tasks (frontal lessons): Introduction to motion estimation and problem formulation. Implementation of motion estimation algorithms (e.g. exhaustive search, 3-step search) and testing on synthetic datasets using Matlab. Analysis of computational complexity of the proposed motion estimation algorithms. Implementation and testing on real world data using Matlab. Review of fundamentals of video coding (which was covered in the main course). Summary of the comparison among different standards (i.e. H.261, MPEG-1, MPEG-2). Introduction and use of ffmpeg libraries with different configuration settings. Review of H.264 standard. Introduction and use of the H.264/AVC JM reference software manual.

Project description: design and implementation of an algorithm for summarization of consumer videos.

Student Supervision and Assessment: Michele Vascotto

Publications

2020	l (oulomb	Autoencoders
2020	Couloillo	Autocilcodeis

E. Sansone, H. T. Ali, J. Sun

To appear in European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI)

2018 Towards Uncovering the True Use of Unlabeled Data in Machine Learning

E. Sansone PhD Thesis

2018 Efficient Training for Positive Unlabeled Learning

E. Sansone, F.G.B De Natale, Z.H. Zhou

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Asnalysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), [Code]

2017 Training Feedforward Neural Networks with Standard Logistic Activations is Feasible

E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale

arXiv pre-print

2017 Automatic Synchronization of Multi-User Photo Galleries

E. Sansone, K. Apostolidis, N. Conci, G. Boato, V. Mezaris, F.G.B. De Natale

IEEE Transactions on Multimedia (TMM), [Code]

2016 Classtering: Joint Classification and Clustering with Mixture of Factor Analysers

E. Sansone, A. Passerini, F.G.B. De Natale

European Conference on Artificial Intelligence (ECAI), [Code]

2014 Synchronizing Multi-User Photo Galleries with MRF

E. Sansone, G. Boato, MS. Dao

MediaEval Workshop

2013 Event Clustering and Classification from Social Media: Watershed-based and Kernel

Methods

TV. Nguyen, MS. Dao, R. Mattivi, E. Sansone, F.G.B. De Natale, G. Boato

MediaEval Workshop

Invited Talks

2019 Coulomb Autoencoders

Symposium on Deep Generative Models, British Computer Society (London, UK)

2017 Generative Adversarial Networks

Fondazione Bruno Kessler (Trento, Italy)

Awards

2016 Academic Hardware Grant Award, NVIDIA

Award consisting of a NVIDIA Titan X GPU

Description: Independently writing a proposal for research grant

2012 Merit Award, University of Trento

Trento, Italy

Award assigned to distinguished master students

Learning Certificates

2020 Algorithms Specialization

Certificate of completion

Organization: Coursera (Stanford University)

2018 Full Stack Deep Learning Bootcamp

Berkeley, USA

Certificate of completion

Organization: University of California, Berkeley

2017 Neural Networks for Machine Learning

Certificate of completion

Organization: Coursera (University of Toronto)

2015 Machine Learning Summer School

Austin, USA

Certificate of completion

Organization: University of Texas at Austin

Sport Professional Experience

2011-to date

Ski master instructor

Italy

This is the highest professional degree in alpine skiing (the total number of ski master instructors in Italy is around 200), which can be achieved by demonstrating excellent skiing capabilities as well as strong organizational, didactical and methodological skills used in teaching.

I hold several professional education and training courses for ski instructors and candidate ski instructors. The following is a list of people I prepared to become ski instructors: Alessandro Berlanda, Camilla Berlanda, Martina Kerschbaumer, Davide Raineri, Valentina Zampedri, Erman Baldessari, Federico Tonezzer, Martina Longobardi, Chiara Villotti, Stefano Gonzo, Francesca Cella, Samuel Piffer, Teo Valle, Martino Santoni, Emma Santoni, Thomas Corradino, Silvia Zeni, Marco Faccenda.

2007-2017

Ski coach

Italy

Coach of young athletes (6-20 years old) in several racing ski teams: Ski Team Sopramonte (2007/2008), Sci Club Padova (2008/2009), Sci Club Panarotta (2009-2011), Ski Team Paganella (2013/2014), Campiglio Ski Team (2016/2017).

2002-2007

Ski athlete

Italy

Participating in many international competitions. See a sample list of records.

Sport Certificates

2011 Ski Master Instructor

Milan, Italy Certificate

Organization: FISI, CoScuMa

2011 Ski Coach (3° level)

Milan, Italy Certificate

Organization: FISI, STF

2007 Ski Instructor

Trento, Italy
Certificate
Organization: PAT

Languages

Italian: Mothertongue
English: Fluent (C2)
German: Fluent (B2)

Other Interests

Blogging

Recently, I've discovered blogging as a way to share thoughts and notes about topics in machine learning.

Volunteering

From 2012 to 2014, I've been member of a no-profit association, GiPro, composed by young representatives of different sectors (e.g. ski instructors, engineers, lawyers, psychologists). The goal of the association is to promote the professional categories on the territory and stimulate the inter-professional collaboration of young

people.

Others

I like playing soccer and hiking.